emeritus.org 2016-10-31

# EMERITUS Institute of Management - Privacy Policy

This website is owned and operated by the EMERITUS Institute of Management, hereinafter referred to as “EMERITUS”. This Privacy Policy only applies to information that we collect through the EMERITUS Website (the “Site,” which consists of all content and pages located within the EMERITUS.org web domain) and does not apply to information that we may collect from you in other ways (for example, this policy does not apply to information that you may provide to us over the phone, by fax, or through conventional mail).

We may log the IP address, operating system, and browser software used by each user of the Site, and we may be able to determine from an IP address a user’s Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. Various web analytics tools are used to collect this information. Some of the information is collected through cookies. If you reject our cookies, many functions and conveniences of this Site may not work properly. Although user sessions are tracked, the users remain anonymous.

As a responsible private educational institution, EMERITUS is committed to maintaining a high standard of confidentiality with respect to the personal data of our students, alumni, employees and faculty in accordance with the requirements of the Personal Data Protection Act 2012 (the “PDPA”), Singapore. For more information about the PDPA, please visit the Personal Data Protection Commission’s website at [http://www.pdpc.gov.sg](http://www.pdpc.gov.sg/).

To safeguard your personal data, all electronic storage and transmission of personal data are secured with appropriate security technologies.

“Personal Data” is defined under the PDPA to mean personal information, whether true or not and whether in electronic or other form, about an individual who can be identified:

  1. from that data; or
  2. from that data and other information to which we have access to  
or are likely to have access to.

Examples of personal data are your name, address, NRIC/FIN/Passport number, photograph or video image, telephone numbers and email addresses.

To find out more about PDPA, you may visit the Singapore Personal Data Protection Commission’s website at [http://www.pdpc.gov.sg](http://www.pdpc.gov.sg/).

EMERITUS and its partners, including its University partners (collectively “EMERITUS”, “we” or “us”) collect, use and disclose your personal data for the following purposes in connection with the products or services which you have applied for, to the extent applicable:

  1. General administration of your application and/or registration and/or enquiry, including those personal data collected by our recruitment agents, for any programme offered by us or our University partners;.
  2. To help us improve our offerings, both individually (e.g., by course staff when working with a student) and in aggregate, and to individualize the experience and to evaluate the access and use of the Site
  3. For purposes of scientific research
  4. For the purpose for which you specifically provided the information, for example, to respond to a specific inquiry or provide you with access to the specific course content and/or services you select.
  5. To track both individual and aggregate attendance, progress and completion of a course, and to analyze statistics on student performance and how students learn.
  6. To monitor and detect violations as well as other misuses and  
potential misuses of the Site.
  7. To send you updates about courses offered by EMERITUS or other events, to send you communications about products or services of EMERITUS, EMERITUS affiliates, or selected business partners that may be of interest to you, or to send you email messages about Site maintenance or updates.
  8. To authenticate your identity when needed
  9. To process refunds, as applicable.
  10. Conducting checks with the DO NOT CALL Registry;
  11. Internal policies and procedures and any applicable laws, rules, regulations, codes of practice or guidelines, orders or requests issued by any court, legal or regulatory bodies (including but not limited to disclosures to regulatory bodies, conducting audit checks, surveillance and investigation);
  12. For purposes described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy (including, e.g., Sharing with Third Parties).
  13. As otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

By providing the Personal Data, including those related to a third party (e.g: information of your parents) to us through the various channels (e.g: written form, webpage), you represent and warrant that consent, including that of the third party, has been obtained for collection, use and disclosure of the Personal Data for the respective purposes.

EMERITUS ensures that your Personal Data held by us shall be kept confidential. When transferring personal data to our third party service providers, agents and/or our affiliates or related corporations whether in Singapore or elsewhere in order to carry out one or more of the purposes listed above, we will require them to ensure that your Personal Data disclosed to them is kept confidential and secure.

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. They will need access to your personal information needed to perform their functions for EMERITUS, but may not use it for other purposes. We will share information we collect with third parties as follows:

  1. With service providers or contractors that perform certain functions on our Site, including managing our learning management system, hosting our videos and course ware, processing information that you provide to us on the Site, processing purchases via third party providers, and other transactions through the Site, operating the Site or portions of it, providing or administering courses, or in connection with other aspects of EMERITUS services.
  2. With other visitors to the Site, course platform or our mobile learning app, to the extent that you submit comments, course work, or other information or content (collectively, “Postings”) to a portion of the Site, course platform or mobile learning app designed for public communications; and with other members of an EMERITUS class of which you are a member, to the extent you submit Postings to a portion of the Site, course platform or mobile learning app designed for viewing by those class members. We may provide your Postings to students who later enroll in the same classes as you, within the context of the forums, the courseware, or otherwise. If we do re-post your Postings originally made to non-public portions of the Site, course platform or mobile learning application or learning management system we will post them without your real name and e-mail (except with your express permission), but we may use your username without your consent.
  3. For purposes of scientific research, particularly, for example, in the areas of cognitive science and education. However, we will only share Personal Information about you for this purpose to the extent doing so complies with applicable law and is limited to the Personal Information required to fulfill the purposes stated at the time of collection.
  4. To provide opportunities for you to communicate with other users who may have similar interests or educational goals. For instance, we may recommend specific study groups or connect potential student and coaches. In such cases, we may use all information collected about you to determine who might be interested in communicating with you.
  5. To respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to investigate, or prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or security or technical issues, or to enforce our terms and conditions, or this Privacy Policy; as otherwise may be required by applicable law; or to protect our rights, property, or safety or those of others.
  6. With affiliates of EMERITUS or with successors in the event of a merger, acquisition or reorganization, for their use consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  7. As otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.
  8. For integration with third party services.

In addition, we may share aggregated information that does not personally identify you with the public and with third parties, including but not limited to researchers and business partners.

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal data online – for example on message boards, through e-mails, or in chat areas – that information can be collected and used by others. By posting personal data online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

The Site contains links to websites published by third parties, including other content providers as well as certain service providers, such as those who process payments on behalf of EMERITUS. These other websites are not under our control, and you acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by such websites, unless we have otherwise indicated in this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to be aware when you are be redirected to a third party website and review the privacy policies of each website you visit and use.

Please note that we review and may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. When changes are made, the Privacy Policy link will include a notation “Revised (date).” indicating that you should review the new terms, which will be effective immediately upon posting on this page, with an updated effective date. The notation will be included in the Privacy Policy link for at least seven (7) days after the update has been made. By accessing the Site after any changes have been made, you signify your agreement on a prospective basis to the modified Privacy Policy and any changes contained therein. In case you miss the notification referenced above, be sure to return to this page periodically to ensure familiarity with the most current version of this Privacy Policy.

If you have privacy concerns, have disclosed data you would prefer to keep private, or would like to access the information we maintain about you, please contact us at privacy@EMERITUS.org.

**Effective Date: October 25, 2015**
